Guide to the Dorothy Frooks Papers 1897-1984 MS 3116
New-York Historical Society
- Various Documents, 1900s-1910s, 1908-1919, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Among other documents includes: two copies of Vol. 1/No. 1 of Public Service Magazine, one marked "diary copy"; Vol. 1/No. 1 of American Patriot publication; negative photoreproductions of two letters from William Jennings Bryan; a few clippings related to suffrage and World War I activities; publicity flyers for Frooks's availability as a speaker; letters of support from the Business Men's League for creating a women's branch; letters and certifications related to the Liberty Loan campaign and Frook's naval service (with related follow-on letters dated 1943); dust jacket/publicity for "American Heart.".
- Various Documents, 1920s, 1920s, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Among other documents includes blank Republican candidate nomination form for Frooks (1920); statement of candidate Frooks before Taxpayers Association; Alfred E. Smith delegate campaign flyer; photoreproduction of certification of Frooks as member of the Presbyterian Church; Frooks's booklet "Wills"; Nomad Lecture Bureau booklet, with Frooks; Nomad flyers featuring Frooks; program for Business and Professional Women's Club meeting with Frooks as speaker; booklet "The True Story of Mary and Her Little Lamb" by Elsie Eunice Sawyer (1927, with what appears to be a 1961 inscription from Alfred Altman); Frooks's article "Women's Political Party" in the National Democratic Review; two recommendations to Governor Roosevelt to name Frooks to Children's Court; a letter from Ruth Bryan Owen acknowledging receipt of "Love's Law" and thanking Frooks for her campaign help in 1926.
- Various Documents, 1930s, 1932-1939 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Among other documents includes an announcement for Frooks's appearance in support of her book "All in Love"; pamphlet of programs to be broadcast over W1XAL short wave (1936); programs for the Perfume and Cosmetic Buyers Conference at the Hotel Commodore (1935) and the Women World War Veterans luncheon at the American Legion Convention (1937); seating directory for the Claude G. Bowers testimonial dinner at the Hotel Astor for the benefit of Monticello (1933); complimentary letter from Dorothy Dix acknowledging receipt of book (1933); acknowledgement of Frooks's membership in Patriots' Roll Call in connection with celebration of George Washington 200th birthday anniversary (1932); "U.S. Coast Guard" magazine with article on Frooks (1939).
- Various Documents, 1940s, 1940-1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Among other documents includes an invitation to the Women World War Veterans' Committee for the Peace Dinner (1940); a personal letter from Edward C. (Ned) Caswell, with two of his hand-drawn illustrations (1941); letter and ribbons regarding Frooks's election as an alternate delegate from American Legion Quentin Roosevelt Post No. 4 to the annual convention (1942); thanks from the USO Speakers Bureau and encouragement to join the Navy Waves (1942); letter of recommendation from attorney William Cattron Rigby for Frooks to the U.S. Court of Appeals (1943); fundraising letter for the U.S. Olympic Committee directed at the Negligee Manufacturers Association on behalf of Frooks (1948).
- Various Documents, World War II, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  This folder includes documents related to Frooks's service in the Women's Army Corps during World War II. Includes several snapshots of her and other women in uniform, passes, qualification certificate, special orders, pay allotment forms, information booklet for Camp Sibert, Alabama, and a brochure for Hotel Warm Springs, Georgia.
- Various Documents, 1950s (2 folders), 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
  Among other documents includes a snapshot of Frooks and others at the Father Duffy monument (1951); programs for an American Legion Post dance, inscribed by New York Mayor Vincent R. Impellitteri (1953), American Gold Star Mothers banquet (1956), Retreads New York County Hut No. 5 dinner-dance (1956), and United Taxpayers Party dinner dance (1958); seating lists for NY State Bar Association dinner (1956)and IDC Honor Awards (1958); three letters from the Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge (1956); photoreproduction of letter from John J. O'Connor declining to run for governor and commenting on Tammany Hall politics (1958); and Frooks's remarks before the United Taxpayers Party (1958). In second folder are two issues of the "Murray Hill News": December 1954 and October 1955 (2 copies) and a Caswell image of Frooks's as Salvation Army attorney (undated but found with the newspapers).
- Various Documents, 1960s (2 folders), 1961-1969 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  Among other documents includes a letter from William J. Ronan (Secretary to the New York Governor) regarding Frook's letter on the operation of hospitals (Frooks's letter not in file) and a few other letters (1961); letter from Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy thanking Frooks's for her note regarding the similarity of the words "peace" and "world" in the Russian language (1961); Murray Hill News certificate of membership in Accredited Home Newspapers of America (1964); copy of the Murray Hill News (September 1964) and article in the News on Frooks's trip to Bermuda and Nassau (1961); two legal resolutions presented by Frooks (1964); Who's Who biography (1965); two photographs related to the Salvation Army and U.S. Post Office (1965); citation from Veterans of World War I (1967) and notice of election as National Judge Advocate for the organization (1968); brochure for art show to benefit the Murray Hill Barracks of the Veterans of WWI (1968); program for the national convention of the Verterans of World War I of the USA and Ladies Auxiliary (1969).
- Various Documents, 1970s (2 folders), 1970-1977 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
  Among other documents includes Frooks's booklet "How to Use Small Claims Court" (1977); publicity-related materials for her books "Lady Lawyer" and "Are You a Happy American" (including two photographs with co-author and brother Richard Frooks and others); various certificates and citations; a newsletter from the International Alfred Lichtenstein Fan Club, which honored Frooks (1973); invitation to the Order of Lafayette's Freedom Award Dinner (1973); souvenir program of the Westchester County Bar Association banquet, with reference to Frooks; seating list for NY State Bar Assciation dinner (1974); New York City Conservative Campaign Committee candidate list (1973); tearsheets and clippings (including her 1972 report for the Murray Hill News on her trip to Monte Carlo, Spain and Portugal).
- Various Documents, 1980s, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Holds Frooks's booklet "Wills" (1980); seating list for Westchester County Bar Association dinner (1983); documents regarding Frooks's appearance at the Saw Mill Road School for Women's History Week (1983); and two clippings, including one concerning her appearance as a "witness" in Warren Beatty's film "Reds" (1982).
- Various Documents, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Includes stationery from various organizations that includes Frooks's name; a Frooks and Frooks business card and change of address card; certificate of charter membership from the World Peace Through Law Center; a Who's Who's entry; card with Frooks's poem "Our Creed," and some clippings.
- Various Documents, Oversize. Collages, 1910s-1930s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Several oversize sheets of photoreproductions of mostly newspaper clippings about Frooks arranged in collage form.
- Various Documents, Oversize. Clippings, 1926-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Various Documents, Oversize. Posters and Certificates, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Three copies of "Wake up America!" poster from Women World War Veterans publicizing speakers on the subject of domestic and foreign subversion (1950); certificate of membership in Inter-American Bar Association (laminated) (1960); municipal court judge campaign poster(?); certificate of membership in the Nova Scotia Order of the Good Time (circa 1960).
- Various Documents, Oversize. Photographs, 1930s-1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Includes three portraits of unidentified men (two are inscribed, but not legible), circa 1932; a set of nine proof portraits of Frooks in her Red Cross uniform (1943); 3rd annual convention of the Retreads, Department of New York, meal gathering (1950); portrait of Guatemalan president Carlos Castillo Armas, inscribed to Frooks (May 14, 1955).